Page 1 of 15

Standard Contractual Clauses

For the purposes of Article 28(3) of Regulation 2016/679 (the GDPR)

between

(the data controller)

and

SkillUp (Pty) Ltd.

K2015/263362/15

33 Bishoplea ave, Newlands 7700

Cape Town, South Africa

(the data processor)

each a ‘party’; together ‘the parties’

HAVE AGREED on the following Contractual Clauses (the Clauses) in order to meet the

requirements of the GDPR and to ensure the protection of the rights of the data subject.

Standard Contractual Clauses April 2022

Page 2 of 15

1. Table of Contents

2\. Preamble 4

3\. The rights and obligations of the data controller 4

4\. The data processor acts according to instructions 5

5\. Confidentiality 5

6\. Security of processing 5

7\. Use of sub-processors 6

8\. Transfer of data to third countries or international organisations 7

9\. Assistance to the data controller 7

10\. Notification of personal data breach 9

11\. Erasure and return of data 9

12\. Audit and inspection 9

13\. The parties’ agreement on other terms 10

14\. Commencement and termination 10

15\. Data controller and data processor contacts/contact points 10

Appendix A Information about the processing 12

Appendix B Authorised sub-processors 13

Appendix C Instruction pertaining to the use of personal data 14

Appendix D The parties’ terms of agreement on other subjects 17

Standard Contractual Clauses April 2022

Page 3 of 15

2. Preamble

1. These Contractual Clauses (the Clauses) set out the rights and obligations of the

data controller and the data processor, when processing personal data on behalf of

the data controller.

2. The Clauses have been designed to ensure the parties’ compliance with Article

28(3) of Regulation 2016/679 of the European Parliament and of the Council of 27

April 2016 on the protection of natural persons with regard to the processing of

personal data and on the free movement of such data and repealing Directive

95/46/EC (General Data Protection Regulation).

3. In the context of the provision of Lessonspace online classroom

(thelessonspace.com), the data processor will process personal data on behalf of

the data controller in accordance with the Clauses.

4. The Clauses shall take priority over any similar provisions contained in other

agreements between the parties.

5. Four appendices are attached to the Clauses and form an integral part of the

Clauses.

6. Appendix A contains details about the processing of personal data, including the

purpose and nature of the processing, type of personal data, categories of data

subject and duration of the processing.

7. Appendix B contains the data controller’s conditions for the data processor’s use of

sub-processors and a list of sub-processors authorised by the data controller.

8. Appendix C contains the data controller’s instructions with regards to the processing

of personal data, the minimum security measures to be implemented by the data

processor and how audits of the data processor and any sub-processors are to be

performed.

9. Appendix D contains provisions for other activities which are not covered by the

Clauses.

10\. The Clauses along with appendices shall be retained in writing, including

electronically, by both parties.

11\. The Clauses shall not exempt the data processor from obligations to which the data

processor is subject pursuant to the General Data Protection Regulation (the GDPR)

or other legislation.

3. The rights and obligations of the data controller

1. The data controller is responsible for ensuring that the processing of personal data

takes place in compliance with the GDPR (see Article 24 GDPR), the applicable EU

or Member State data protection provisions and the Clauses.1

1 References to ”Member States” made throughout the Clauses shall be understood as references to “EEA Member States”.

Standard Contractual Clauses April 2022

Page 4 of 15

2. The data controller has the right and obligation to make decisions about the

purposes and means of the processing of personal data.

3. The data controller shall be responsible, among other, for ensuring that the

processing of personal data, which the data processor is instructed to perform, has a

legal basis.

4. The data processor acts according to instructions

1. The data processor shall process personal data only on documented instructions

from the data controller, unless required to do so by Union or Member State law to

which the processor is subject. Such instructions shall be specified in appendices A

and C. Subsequent instructions can also be given by the data controller throughout

the duration of the processing of personal data, but such instructions shall always be

documented and kept in writing, including electronically, in connection with the

Clauses.

2. The data processor shall immediately inform the data controller if instructions given

by the data controller, in the opinion of the data processor, contravene the GDPR or

the applicable EU or Member State data protection provisions.

5. Confidentiality

1. The data processor shall only grant access to the personal data being processed on

behalf of the data controller to persons under the data processor’s authority who

have committed themselves to confidentiality or are under an appropriate statutory

obligation of confidentiality and only on a need to know basis. The list of persons to

whom access has been granted shall be kept under periodic review. On the basis of

this review, such access to personal data can be withdrawn, if access is no longer

necessary, and personal data shall consequently not be accessible anymore to

those persons.

2. The data processor shall at the request of the data controller demonstrate that the

concerned persons under the data processor’s authority are subject to the

abovementioned confidentiality.

6. Security of processing

1. Article 32 GDPR stipulates that, taking into account the state of the art, the costs of

implementation and the nature, scope, context and purposes of processing as well

as the risk of varying likelihood and severity for the rights and freedoms of natural

persons, the data controller and data processor shall implement appropriate

technical and organisational measures to ensure a level of security appropriate to

the risk.

The data controller shall evaluate the risks to the rights and freedoms of natural

persons inherent in the processing and implement measures to mitigate those risks.

Depending on their relevance, the measures may include the following:

- Pseudonymisation and encryption of personal data;

- the ability to ensure ongoing confidentiality, integrity, availability and resilience of

processing systems and services;

Standard Contractual Clauses April 2022

Page 5 of 15

- the ability to restore the availability and access to personal data in a timely

manner in the event of a physical or technical incident;

- a process for regularly testing, assessing and evaluating the effectiveness of

technical and organisational measures for ensuring the security of the

processing.

2. According to Article 32 GDPR, the data processor shall also – independently from

the data controller – evaluate the risks to the rights and freedoms of natural persons

inherent in the processing and implement measures to mitigate those risks. To this

effect, the data controller shall provide the data processor with all information

necessary to identify and evaluate such risks.

3. Furthermore, the data processor shall assist the data controller in ensuring

compliance with the data controller’s obligations pursuant to Articles 32 GDPR, by

inter alia providing the data controller with information concerning the technical and

organisational measures already implemented by the data processor pursuant to

Article 32 GDPR along with all other information necessary for the data controller to

comply with the data controller’s obligation under Article 32 GDPR.

If subsequently – in the assessment of the data controller – mitigation of the

identified risks require further measures to be implemented by the data processor,

than those already implemented by the data processor pursuant to Article 32 GDPR,

the data controller shall specify these additional measures to be implemented in

Appendix C.

7. Use of sub-processors

1. The data processor shall meet the requirements specified in Article 28(2) and (4)

GDPR in order to engage another processor (a sub-processor).

2. The data processor shall therefore not engage another processor (sub-processor)

for the fulfilment of the Clauses without the prior general written authorisation of the

data controller.

3. The data processor has the data controller’s general authorisation for the

engagement of sub-processors. The data processor shall inform in writing the data

controller of any intended changes concerning the addition or replacement of

sub-processors at least 14 days in advance, thereby giving the data controller the

opportunity to object to such changes prior to the engagement of the concerned

sub-processor(s). Longer time periods of prior notice for specific sub-processing

services can be provided in Appendix B. The list of sub-processors already

authorised by the data controller can be found in Appendix B.

4. Where the data processor engages a sub-processor for carrying out specific

processing activities on behalf of the data controller, the same data protection

obligations as set out in the Clauses shall be imposed on that sub-processor by way

of a contract or other legal act under EU or Member State law, in particular providing

sufficient guarantees to implement appropriate technical and organisational

measures in such a manner that the processing will meet the requirements of the

Clauses and the GDPR.

Standard Contractual Clauses April 2022

Page 6 of 15

The data processor shall therefore be responsible for requiring that the

sub-processor at least complies with the obligations to which the data processor is

subject pursuant to the Clauses and the GDPR.

5. A copy of such a sub-processor agreement and subsequent amendments shall – at

the data controller’s request – be submitted to the data controller, thereby giving the

data controller the opportunity to ensure that the same data protection obligations as

set out in the Clauses are imposed on the sub-processor. Clauses on business

related issues that do not affect the legal data protection content of the

sub-processor agreement, shall not require submission to the data controller.

6. The data processor shall agree a third-party beneficiary clause with the

sub-processor where – in the event of bankruptcy of the data processor – the data

controller shall be a third-party beneficiary to the sub-processor agreement and shall

have the right to enforce the agreement against the sub-processor engaged by the

data processor, e.g. enabling the data controller to instruct the sub-processor to

delete or return the personal data.

7. If the sub-processor does not fulfil his data protection obligations, the data processor

shall remain fully liable to the data controller as regards the fulfilment of the

obligations of the sub-processor. This does not affect the rights of the data subjects

under the GDPR – in particular those foreseen in Articles 79 and 82 GDPR – against

the data controller and the data processor, including the sub-processor.

8. Transfer of data to third countries or international organisations

1. Any transfer of personal data to third countries or international organisations by the

data processor shall only occur on the basis of documented instructions from the

data controller and shall always take place in compliance with Chapter V GDPR.

2. In case transfers to third countries or international organisations, which the data

processor has not been instructed to perform by the data controller, is required

under EU or Member State law to which the data processor is subject, the data

processor shall inform the data controller of that legal requirement prior to

processing unless that law prohibits such information on important grounds of public

interest.

3. Without documented instructions from the data controller, the data processor

therefore cannot within the framework of the Clauses:

a. transfer personal data to a data controller or a data processor in a third

country or in an international organization

b. transfer the processing of personal data to a sub-processor in a third

country

c. have the personal data processed in by the data processor in a third

country

4. The data controller’s instructions regarding the transfer of personal data to a third

country including, if applicable, the transfer tool under Chapter V GDPR on which

they are based, shall be set out in Appendix C.6.

Standard Contractual Clauses April 2022

Page 7 of 15

5. The Clauses shall not be confused with standard data protection clauses within the

meaning of Article 46(2)(c) and (d) GDPR, and the Clauses cannot be relied upon by

the parties as a transfer tool under Chapter V GDPR.

9. Assistance to the data controller

1. Taking into account the nature of the processing, the data processor shall assist the

data controller by appropriate technical and organisational measures, insofar as this

is possible, in the fulfilment of the data controller’s obligations to respond to requests

for exercising the data subject’s rights laid down in Chapter III GDPR.

This entails that the data processor shall, insofar as this is possible, assist the data

controller in the data controller’s compliance with:

a. the right to be informed when collecting personal data from the data subject

b. the right to be informed when personal data have not been obtained from

the data subject

c. the right of access by the data subject

d. the right to rectification

e. the right to erasure (‘the right to be forgotten’)

f. the right to restriction of processing

g. notification obligation regarding rectification or erasure of personal data or

restriction of processing

h. the right to data portability

i. the right to object

j. the right not to be subject to a decision based solely on automated

processing, including profiling

2. In addition to the data processor’s obligation to assist the data controller pursuant to

Clause 6.3., the data processor shall furthermore, taking into account the nature of

the processing and the information available to the data processor, assist the data

controller in ensuring compliance with:

a. The data controller’s obligation to without undue delay and, where feasible,

not later than 72 hours after having become aware of it, notify the personal

data breach to a competent supervisory authority if applicable, unless the

personal data breach is unlikely to result in a risk to the rights and freedoms

of natural persons;

b. the data controller’s obligation to without undue delay communicate the

personal data breach to the data subject, when the personal data breach is

likely to result in a high risk to the rights and freedoms of natural persons;

c. the data controller’s obligation to carry out an assessment of the impact of

the envisaged processing operations on the protection of personal data (a

data protection impact assessment);

d. the data controller’s obligation to consult a competent supervisory authority,

if applicable, prior to processing where a data protection impact

assessment indicates that the processing would result in a high risk in the

absence of measures taken by the data controller to mitigate the risk.

Standard Contractual Clauses April 2022

Page 8 of 15

3. The parties shall define in Appendix C the appropriate technical and organisational

measures by which the data processor is required to assist the data controller as

well as the scope and the extent of the assistance required. This applies to the

obligations foreseen in Clause 9.1. and 9.2.

10. Notification of personal data breach

1. In case of any personal data breach, the data processor shall, without undue delay

after having become aware of it, notify the data controller of the personal data

breach.

2. The data processor’s notification to the data controller shall, if possible, take place

within 48 hours after the data processor has become aware of the personal data

breach to enable the data controller to comply with the data controller’s obligation to

notify the personal data breach to the competent supervisory authority, cf. Article 33

GDPR.

3. In accordance with Clause 9(2)(a), the data processor shall assist the data controller

in notifying the personal data breach to the competent supervisory authority,

meaning that the data processor is required to assist in obtaining the information

listed below which, pursuant to Article 33(3)GDPR, shall be stated in the data

controller’s notification to the competent supervisory authority:

a. The nature of the personal data including where possible, the categories

and approximate number of data subjects concerned and the categories

and approximate number of personal data records concerned;

b. the likely consequences of the personal data breach;

c. the measures taken or proposed to be taken by the controller to address

the personal data breach, including, where appropriate, measures to

mitigate its possible adverse effects.

4. The parties shall define in Appendix C all the elements to be provided by the data

processor when assisting the data controller in the notification of a personal data

breach to the competent supervisory authority.

11. Erasure and return of data

1. On termination of the provision of personal data processing services, the data

processor shall be under obligation to return all the personal data to the data

controller and delete existing copies unless Union or Member State law requires

storage of the personal data.

The data processor commits to exclusively process the personal data for the

purposes and duration provided for by this law and under the strict applicable

conditions.

12. Audit and inspection

1. The data processor shall make available to the data controller all information

necessary to demonstrate compliance with the obligations laid down in Article 28

Standard Contractual Clauses April 2022

Page 9 of 15

and the Clauses and allow for and contribute to audits, including inspections,

conducted by the data controller or another auditor mandated by the data controller.

2. Procedures applicable to the data controller’s audits, including inspections, of the

data processor and sub-processors are specified in appendices C.7. and C.8.

3. The data processor shall be required to provide the supervisory authorities, which

pursuant to applicable legislation have access to the data controller’s and data

processor’s facilities, or representatives acting on behalf of such supervisory

authorities, with access to the data processor’s physical facilities on presentation of

appropriate identification.

13. The parties’ agreement on other terms

1. The parties may agree to other clauses concerning the provision of the personal

data processing service specifying e.g. liability, as long as they do not contradict

directly or indirectly the Clauses or prejudice the fundamental rights or freedoms of

the data subject and the protection afforded by the GDPR.

14. Commencement and termination

1. The Clauses shall become effective on the date of both parties’ signature.

2. Both parties shall be entitled to require the Clauses renegotiated if changes to the

law or inexpediency of the Clauses should give rise to such renegotiation.

3. The Clauses shall apply for the duration of the provision of personal data processing

services. For the duration of the provision of personal data processing services, the

Clauses cannot be terminated unless other Clauses governing the provision of

personal data processing services have been agreed between the parties.

4. If the provision of personal data processing services is terminated, and the personal

data is deleted or returned to the data controller pursuant to Clause 11.1. and

Appendix C.4., the Clauses may be terminated by written notice by either party.

5. Signature

On behalf of the data controller

Name

Position

Date

Signature

On behalf of the data processor

Standard Contractual Clauses April 2022

Page 10 of 15

Name Matthew Henshall

Position CEO

Signature

15. Data controller and data processor contacts/contact points

1. The parties may contact each other using the following contacts/contact points:

2. The parties shall be under obligation continuously to inform each other of changes to

contacts/contact points.

Name

Position

E-mail

Name Matthew Henshall

Position CEO

E-mail matthew@thelessonspace.com

Standard Contractual Clauses April 2022

Page 11 of 15

Appendix A Information about the processing

A.1. The purpose of the data processor’s processing of personal data on behalf of the

data controller is:

The administration of the data controller’s services of the data processor's web-based

self-service system thelessonspace.com.

The system helps the data controller to manage and review their services including; session

attendees’; durations of sessions and session feedback.

A.2. The data processor’s processing of personal data on behalf of the data controller

shall mainly pertain to (the nature of the processing):

The data controller’s use of the web-based self-service system thelessonspace.com.

A.3. The processing includes the following types of personal data about data subjects:

The standard configuration of the self-service system is that only names and emails are

processed. Both are optional in the standard configuration.

The data controller has full control over the configuration of audio and video recording during

the duration of the session.

When the data controller's users use the service the system automatically does what the

data controller's specifies as default data collections requirements.

A.4. Processing includes the following categories of data subject:

● Persons invited to the data controller's sessions.

● The data controller's users, who are the persons who through a username manage

the data controller's events in the administration area on the data controller's

account in the self-service system.

A.5. The data processor’s processing of personal data on behalf of the data controller

may be performed when the Clauses commence. Processing has the following

duration:

The processing is not time-limited and is performed until the data processor no longer stores

the personal data being processed on behalf of the data controller. A description of the

storage periods and erasure procedures is provided in Appendix C.4 of this data processing

agreement.

Standard Contractual Clauses April 2022

Page 12 of 15

Appendix B Authorised sub-processors

B.1. Approved sub-processors

On commencement of the Clauses, the data controller authorises the engagement of the

following sub-processors:

1. Amazon Web Services (Cloud servers for the storage and hosting of sessions)

The data controller shall on the commencement of the Clauses authorise the use of the

abovementioned sub-processors for the processing described for that party. The data

processor shall not be entitled – without the data controller’s explicit written authorisation – to

engage a sub-processor for a ‘different’ processing than the one which has been agreed

upon or have another sub-processor perform the described processing.

B.2. Prior notice for the authorisation of sub-processors

The data processor must follow the procedure in 7.3 above. If the data processor intends to

utilize a sub-data processor which entails a transfer of data to one or more countries, the

data processor must notify the data controller 30 days in advance.

Standard Contractual Clauses April 2022

Page 13 of 15

Appendix C Instruction pertaining to the use of personal data

C.1. The subject of/instruction for the processing

The data processor shall process the personal data of the data controller in the manner in

which the data controller specifies. For adequate control the data controller will be using the

data processors API.

The web-based self-service system automatically does what the data controller's users

specify when using and setting the features in the administration area of the self-services

system. The data processor's processing on behalf of the data controller is therefore

continuously influenced by how the data controller's users use and set the features in the

administration area of the self-service system.

C.2. Security of processing

The level of security shall take into account the volume and the categories of data and data

subjects and the character of the processing of data.

The data processor shall hereafter be entitled and under obligation to make decisions about

the technical and organisational security measures that are to be applied to create the

necessary (and agreed) level of data security.

The data processor shall however – in any event and at a minimum – implement the

following measures that have been agreed with the data controller:

Requirements for pseudonymisation and encryption of personal data:

- Personal data is not to be used for development, tests or similar purposes, unless

the data is fully anonymized or the parties in advance have entered into an

agreement concerning this subject.

Requirements for ensuring ongoing confidentiality, integrity, availability and resilience of

processing systems and services:

- Systems and databases used for processing personal data are kept up to date with

the latest security patches.

- Established technical measures yearly undergo a vulnerability or penetration review.

- Networks are appropriately segmentalized, to secure restricted access to systems or

databases used for processing personal data.

Requirements for the ability to restore the availability and access to personal data in a timely

manner in the event of a physical or technical incident:

- Point in time recovery and daily snapshots are conducted in line with best practices.

- Restore tests are reviewed at least once a year.

Requirements for processes for regularly testing, assessing and evaluating the effectiveness

of technical and organisational measures for ensuring the security of the processing:

- Changes to the systems, databases or networks adhere to procedures, which

ensure maintenance with relevant updates and patches, among these security

patches.

- There is established a formalized administrative procedure for allocating and

removal of user access for personal data.

- User access is reviewed annually.

Requirements for access to data online:

- Access to personal data though the internet is to be done through efficient

encryption and access is given through a secure log-on system.

Standard Contractual Clauses April 2022

Page 14 of 15

Requirements for the protection of data during transmission:

- Personal data in transition must be applied with efficient encryption.

Requirements for the protection of data during storage:

- All personal data in rest must – if possible – be applied with efficient encryption.

- Only authorized personnel are allowed to access personal data.

Requirements for physical security of locations at which personal data are processed:

- Only authorized personnel are to obtain physical access to the premises and data

centre, in which personal data is kept and processed. This is dealt with by cloud

storage providers.

Requirements for the use of home/remote working:

- External access to systems and databases, which is used for processing of personal

data, is done through secure access control.

Requirements for logging:

- Established logging on systems, databases and networks, which is being used for

processing of personal data is covered by the following conditions:

- Activities done by a system administrator and other trusted right owners

- Security breaches concerning:

- Log setup / deactivating of log changes

- Changes of user system permission

- Failed login attempts on systems, databases or networks.

C.3. Assistance to the data controller

The data processor shall insofar as this is possible – within the scope and the extent of the

assistance specified below – assist the data controller in accordance with Clause 9.1. and

9.2. by implementing the following technical and organisational measures:

The data processor must – to the greatest extent possible – make the data controller

self-reliant by implementing features in the user interface.

C.4. Storage period/erasure procedures

If required by the data controller, personal data is stored for up to 3 months after which the

personal data can be automatically erased by the data processor.

Upon termination of the provision of personal data processing services, the data processor

shall either delete or return the personal data in accordance with Clause 11.1., unless the

data controller – after the signature of the contract – has modified the data controller’s

original choice. Such modification shall be documented and kept in writing, including

electronically, in connection with the Clauses.

C.5. Processing location

Processing of the personal data under the Clauses cannot be performed at other locations

than the following without the data controller’s prior written authorisation:

All data can be stored at a predetermined location based on the data controllers preferences.

The defaults are for all spaces created in the EU to be processed in the EU. The storage

location can be forced using the API.

Standard Contractual Clauses April 2022

Page 15 of 15

C.6. Instruction on the transfer of personal data to third countries

If the data controller does not in the Clauses or subsequently provide documented

instructions pertaining to the transfer of personal data to a third country, the data processor

shall not be entitled within the framework of the Clauses to perform such transfer.

The data processor may utilize sub data processors that entail transfers of data to secure

third countries.

If the data processor wishes to use sub-data processors which entails transfer of personal

data to insecure third countries, data processors must:

1. observe the procedure set out in points 7.3 and B.2 of Annex B

2. apply the Commission's standard contractual clauses and

3. apply technical measures in such a way that the information transferred never

becomes available in personable form to any companies, authorities, or any other

organizations from insecure third countries.

C.7. Procedures for the data controller’s audits, including inspections, of the

processing of personal data being performed by the data processor

The data processor shall yearly review its data processing agreement and technical

implementation of the agreement.

The data controller or the data controller’s representative shall in addition have access to

inspect, including physically inspect, the places where the processing of personal data is

carried out by the data processor, including physical facilities as well as systems used for

and related to the processing. Such an inspection shall be performed, when the data

controller deems it required. This excludes approved sub-processors in Appendix B2.

Standard Contractual Clauses April 2022
